啊，
ah,
如果你是一个高强度互联网冲浪选手，
If you are a high-intensity Internet surfer,
而且是一个历史爱好者，
And he is a history lover.
那么你一定知道近年来网友去中仙给曹操陵前送布洛芬的感人事迹。
Then you must know the touching stories of netizens who went to Zhongxian to give ibuprofen to Cao Cao's tomb in recent years.
近来听说曹操高陵门前门可罗雀人烟稀少咋的？
Recently, I heard that the front door of Cao Cao's Gaoling Gate is sparsely populated?
曹丞相你也过气儿了，
Prime Minister Cao, you are out of date, too
不可能，
impossible,
绝对不可能。
Absolutely impossible.
于是我决定去曹操墓里跟他来一次跨越千年的 room 梦。
So I decided to go to Cao Cao's tomb to have a room dream that spans thousands of years.
好，
good,
我们现在打车去曹操高陵，
We are now taking a taxi to Cao Cao Gaoling.
我来之前我一直寻思，
I kept thinking before I came
我怎么着，
What happened to me?
不得打一个曹操专车吗？
Can't you take a special car for Cao Cao?
说曹操曹操到结果发现安阳没有曹操专车，
It was said that Cao Cao came to Anyang and found that there was no special car for Cao Cao.
我现在已经看到曹操的那个高大的雕像了。
I have now seen the tall statue of Cao Cao.
你看大家好呀，
Look, everyone,
欢迎来到浪花江的户外频道。
Welcome to Langhuajiang's outdoor channel.
我现在来到了中国八大古都之一的河南安阳，
I am now in Anyang, Henan, one of the eight ancient capitals of China.
何以安阳呀？
Why Anyang?
殷墟在这里发掘甲骨文在这里现世，
The Yin Ruins are excavated here oracle bone inscriptions appear here,
这里是三千年前的大义商，
This is the Dayi Businessman three thousand years ago.
同时也是见证魏武帝、
At the same time, it is also a witness to Emperor Wu of Wei,
曹操神、
Cao Cao,
武帝、
Emperor Wu,
高欢冉闵、
Gao Huan Ran Min,
慕容这些乱世枭雄们的六朝古都叶城，
Yecheng, the ancient capital of the Six Dynasties, of Murong, these heroes in troubled times,
河北邯郸的朋友们还望海涵呀。
Friends from Handan, Hebei are still willing to let it go.
叶城主体现在确实是在河北邯郸境内，
The Lord of Yecheng is indeed in Handan, Hebei.
但毕竟安阳也沾点啊，
But after all, Anyang is also a little bit involved.
行政区划，
Administrative division,
这不刚好卡在上面了吗？
Isn't this just stuck on it?
现在随我一起去到曹操高陵博物馆。
Now go with me to the Cao Cao Gaoling Museum.
在我身后的就是魏武帝曹操的塑像，
Behind me is the statue of Emperor Wu of Wei Cao.
包括你看塑像上四个字，
Including the four words on the statue you see,
魏武徽边，
Wei Wuhui's border,
这是出自教园的诗词呀，
This is a poem from the teaching garden.
往事越千年。
The past has lasted thousands of years.
魏武辉边东临碣石有一篇，
There is an article on the east side of Wei Wuhui,
包括我们待会儿去看到了整个展厅的名字就叫往事越千年，
Including when we go to see the entire exhibition hall later, it is called the past thousands of years.
看往事越千年，
Look at the past for thousands of years.
此情此景，
This situation,
我要吟诗一首，
I want to recite a poem,
但我要吟诵的这首诗啊，
But this poem I want to recite,
对你的评论可是比较真挚的。
I have a more sincere comment to you.
你说曹丞相，
You say Prime Minister Cao,
我是念还是不念呀？
Should I chant or not?
念为何不念？
Why not recite it?
那我可是要开启夸夸模式了啊，
Then I'm going to turn on the praising mode.
夜中歌开始，
The song begins in the night.
夜则夜城水张水定有一人从此起雄谋运势与文兴。
There must be a man who will start to make great progress and develop his fortune from then on.
君臣兄弟，
Brothers of the monarch, ministers,
而父子英雄未有俗，
But father and son heroes are not vulgar.
胸中出没，
Invasive in the chest,
岂随人言底，
How can it follow people's words?
英守最魁非两人一丑流芳本义身英雄有神本有戚，
Yingshou’s most famous two people are ugly and beautiful, and the hero has a god and a relative.
岂能苟尔化，
How can you be transformed?
有意笑留住台俱太昂，
I mean to keep the Taiwan and the whole thing too proud.
爱与李氏相抵昂。
Love and Li are in oppressed.
爱有斯人不作逆小不为霸大不亡。
If you love someone, you will not betray the small one, and you will not be too domine the big one.
霸王将做儿女名，
The overlord will be the name of his children.
无可奈何终不平孝中明知非有意，
I can't help but be unfair, knowing that I don't mean it,
分乡未可谓无情呜虎古人作事无作隙，
The division of the countryside is not ruthless, the ancients do nothing,
小莫豪华皆有意。
Xiao Mo is all about luxury.
书中轻义中中人种中笑而殊生气。
The book is light and righteous, and the race is laughing and angry.
嗯嗯，
Uh-huh,
我们现在进来的位置就是曹操陵墓的原址。
The place where we are now coming in is the original site of Cao Cao’s tomb.
你看这是原址的神道，
You see, this is the original Shinto.
还有两边的建筑物。
There are also buildings on both sides.
而我们正对面的就是知名网红打卡处，
And directly opposite us is the well-known internet celebrity check-in place.
曹操高陵网友上供处，
Cao Cao Gaoling netizens came to the confession office,
这边就是曹操高陵之所在附近。
This is near Cao Cao's Gaoling.
你看叶城在这边这边是珍妃的墓，
Look, Ye Cheng is Zhenfei’s tomb here.
这边是一条国道，
This is a national highway.
中间这边就是西门报慈西门报慈溪，
In the middle is Ximen Report Cixi Report Cixi Report Cixi.
就是这个高陵所在地，
It is the location of this Gaoling.
现在我们就要进入曹操死后的家了，
Now we are about to enter the home after Cao Cao's death.
这就是还原的曹操的墓室。
This is the restored Cao Cao's tomb.
我们进来看一下，
Let's come in and take a look.
这就标标准的这个妃墓墓，
This is the standard tomb of this concubine.
大大看看一曹曹操主墓室头顶这个位置，
Take a look at the position above the head of the main tomb of Cao Cao.
这应该就是当时盗墓贼打的盗洞直接打下来。
This should be the hole that the tomb robbers smashed directly at that time.
你看我们现在就在复原的曹操墓室里面。
Look, we are now in the restored Cao Cao’s tomb.
那么为什么确定了这座墓的墓主人就是曹操本人呢？
So why is it confirmed that the owner of this tomb is Cao Cao himself?
其实从这座墓被发现以来，
In fact, since the discovery of this tomb,
就不断有各种的留言与质疑。
There are constant messages and doubts.
比如墓中发现一个小孩的尸体专家称，
For example, the expert said that a child's body was found in the tomb.
这是曹操所时候会不会这是曹操的七十二墓一种之一呢？
Is this one of Cao Cao’s seventy-two tombs?
还有为什么不给曹操去做 DNA 检测？
Also, why not give Cao Cao DNA testing?
其实呀关于这三个谣言和留言，
Actually, about these three rumors and comments,
曹操小时候就是当时的一个短信笑话被传承了新闻七十二遗种本身就是后世加工的传说，
When Cao Cao was a child, he was passed down on a text message joke at that time. The seventy-two kinds of news are themselves legends processed in later generations.
根本不可信，
Not trustworthy at all.
不做 DNA 检测的原因是因为提取的成功率太低，
If you don't do it, the reason for DNA testing is that the success rate of extraction is too low.
并且有谁是真正确凿的？
And who is really chiseled correctly?
曹操后人可供拿来 DNA 比对呢。
Cao Cao’s descendants can provide it with them, and DNA comparison is how to compare.
所以真正的问题只有一个，
So there is only one real problem.
那就是如何通过一个被盗具的陵墓证明墓主人就是曹操。
That is how to prove that the owner of the tomb is Cao Cao through a stolen tomb.
曹操高龄，
Cao Cao is old,
有著名的考古专家唐继根老师主持发掘唐老师，
A famous archaeological expert, Mr. Tang Jigen, presided over the excavation of Mr. Tang.
也是之前殷墟考古工作队的队长。
He is also the captain of the Yinxu Archaeological Team.
所以今天我们有幸讲到了啊，
So today we have the honor to talk about it.
不是是啊，
No,
今天接替曹操师和我为大家讲解的是夸克 a 我我们现在就夸夸克深深度搜索功能解解一一下为什么这座墓葬埋的就当当人曹曹操看一番思考的过后，
Today, the one who succeeded Cao Cao and I explained to you is Quark. A. Let’s now praise the deep search function of Quark to explain why this tomb is buried by Cao Cao Cao after watching and thinking about it.
很快就生成了答案。
The answer was generated soon.
而且特别详细。
And particularly detailed.
首先第一点是关键证据。
The first point is the key evidence.
在这附近发现的一个叫卢浅的人的墓质，
The tomb of a man named Lu Qian was found nearby.
说明了具体指向说卢浅的墓位于魏武帝陵西北角西行四十三步。
It explains that Lu Qian's tomb is located in the northwest corner of the tomb of Emperor Wu of Wei tomb forty-three steps westward.
那么反推就可以知道曹操墓葬的位置了。
Then you can know the location of Cao Cao’s tomb by reverse.
第二点，
The second point,
与史书三国志中记载相吻合，
Consistent with the records in the Three Kingdoms of History,
葬于夜之西岗，
Burial in Xigang at night,
与西门豹祠相近，
It is similar to the Ximen Bao Temple.
位置吻合了。
The position matches.
第三点，
The third point,
墓葬形制符合东汉末年高等级墓葬的特点，
The tomb shape is in line with the characteristics of high-level tombs in the late Eastern Han Dynasty.
出土的五铢钱兵器等，
Unearthed Wuzhu coins weapons, etc.
都是东汉末年的风格，
They are all styles from the late Eastern Han Dynasty.
而且陪葬有石龟石壁尺寸远超诸侯王的级别，
Moreover, the size of the stone turtle and stone wall is far beyond that of the princes and kings.
说明墓主人的身份接近帝王呀。
It means that the identity of the tomb owner is close to that of the emperor.
四、
Four,
墓中出土的石牌上普遍刻有魏武王字样，
The words "Wu of Wei" are generally engraved on the stone plaques unearthed in the tomb.
还有谁是魏武王呢？
Who else is King Wu of Wei?
直接指向了曹操的身份。
It directly points to Cao Cao's identity.
第五点，
The fifth point,
墓中文物中有兵器和文房用品，
The cultural relics in the tomb include weapons and study supplies.
这符合曹操能文能武横朔赋诗的特点呀。
This is in line with the characteristics of Cao Cao's ability to write poetry in literature and martial arts.
第六点，
The sixth point,
出土的这件魏相石，
This Wei Xiang stone unearthed,
也和曹操生平患有头封的记载相一致。
It is also consistent with the records of Cao Cao suffering from a head seal in his life.
第七点，
The seventh point,
石牌上有香囊飒霜，
There is sachet sausage cream on the stone plaque.
符合曹操生前喜欢熏香的特征。
It is in line with Cao Cao's characteristics of fumigation during his lifetime.
他临终前不也是嘱咐那些妻妾们把香都分了吗？
Didn’t he also instruct his wives and concubines to share all the incense before his death?
第八点，
Point 8,
根据尸骨比对逝者的年龄，
According to the age of the deceased,
在六十岁以上，
Over sixty years old,
与曹操六十六岁去世高度吻合，
It is highly consistent with Cao Cao's death at the age of 66.
且根据尸骨推测，
And according to the corpse,
其身材并不高。
He is not tall.
符合史书中记载的曹操姿貌短小的特征。
It conforms to the short-skinned characteristics of Cao Cao recorded in historical books.
种种证据最终指向墓主人几乎可以确定就是曹操本人从回答我们能够看出夸克的深度搜索，
All the evidence finally pointed to the tomb owner, which was almost certain that Cao Cao himself could see the deep search of quarks from the answer.
能够通过搜集最新资料在进行有逻辑的推理分析之后，
After collecting the latest information, after conducting logical inference analysis,
给到更详细可靠的答案。
Give more detailed and reliable answers.
答案。
Answer.
信息员还可以溯源查看。
The information officer can also view the source.
对于这种专业问题的解答，
For answers to such professional questions,
从答案结果来看，
Judging from the answer results,
其准确性、
Its accuracy,
稳定性都有目共睹。
Stability is obvious to all.
关键是免费还干净，
The key is that it is free and clean.
无广告。
No ads.
当初夸克 APP 诞生没多久，
Quark, the APP was born not long ago.
我就在用夸克了，
I'm using quarks.
是妥妥的老用户。
A true old user.
我年前已经给大家安利过他的功能。
I've already recommended his features to you a few years ago.
但是，
but,
短短半年之后，
In just half a year,
接入深度思考后的多模态搜索以及知网为普等权威数据库的支持，
Access to multimodal search after deep thinking and support from CNKI and other authoritative databases,
让夸克搜索变得无比强大，
Make Quark search extremely powerful.
还不抓紧下载抢先体验。
Don't hurry up and download and experience it first.
我们来看这一件独立展柜中的文物是一块石头。
Let’s look at the cultural relics in this independent display cabinet as a stone.
正常他的博物馆简介上只会有一行他的名字说魏武王常所用未象石石疹，
Normally, there is only one line in his museum introduction. His name says that King Wu of Wei often uses stone rash without elephant.
但是更多的信息我们就无从得知了。
But we have no way to know more information.
所以我们用夸克的 AI 相机简单拍一下，
So we use a quark, AI camera to take a simple shot.
照所有的信息，
According to all information,
立马全部都呈现出来说这件石疹其实是渠疹。
It immediately all showed that this stone rash was actually a canal rash.
你看它中间凹槽下来像一个水渠的凹槽一样，
You see the groove in the middle of it is like a groove in a canal.
所以叫曲疹这个东西是怎么用的呢？
So how do you use this thing called curvature?
因为曹操生前患有头风病啊，
Because Cao Cao suffered from cerebral diseases during his lifetime,
所以说在使用这件东西的时候，
So when using this thing,
它是一个医疗器物，
It is a medical instrument.
比如说提前先加热，
For example, heat it up in advance.
但是放在脖子下面来热敷，
But put it under your neck to make a hot compress.
所以叫魏象石像，
So it is called Wei Xiang Stone Statue.
就是脖子呀未向石这些就是曹操墓中出土的石牌。
Just the neck, the stones are unearthed from Cao Cao’s tomb.
接下来我们还会看到很多这些石牌是生前埋葬时候的浅侧，
Next we will see many of these stone tablets that were burial during their lifetime.
就是登记啊，
Just register,
这个墓里陪葬了多少多少器物，
How many utensils were buried in this tomb,
但是器物都已经被盗了，
But the objects have been stolen.
只剩下了这些石制牌，
Only these stone cards are left.
有点像这个超市货架里那些价格小条子。
A bit like the price sticks in this supermarket shelves.
但是我们通过这上面记载的这些器物，
But we use these objects recorded above,
我们也知道当时陪葬了什么，
We also know what was buried at that time.
所以说特别重要，
So it is particularly important.
这是曹操墓中出土的石壁和石龟，
These are stone walls and stone turtles unearthed from Cao Cao’s tomb.
咱们都知道正常是玉璧玉龟，
We all know that it is a jade bi and a jade turtle.
对吧？
Right?
但是你看这都是石质槽，
But you see, these are all stone troughs.
说明那什么一方面是减葬，
It means that on the one hand, it is to reduce burials.
另一方面操操真是很节省省的一个人。
On the other hand, fucking is really a very saving person.
我实实别想知道这个铜印印印的是是什，
I really don't want to know what this copper seal is.
我待待儿搜搜一下一个墓中出土铜印，
I'll search for copper seals unearthed from a tomb.
一般看这个铜印上记载的主人的名字，
Generally, look at the name of the owner recorded on this bronze seal.
你就能确定墓主人的身份，
You can confirm the identity of the tomb owner.
所以我才才了一下。
That's why I just made a moment.
然后目前有几种种法法上面的印的字，
Then there are currently several printed characters on the law.
一种是蛮，
One is barbaric,
就是阿满的。
It's Aman's.
马说这个跟后世阿满的马应该是同一个意思思，
Horse said that this should have the same meaning as Aman's horse in later generations.
有说是一个个曹的，
Some say they are all Cao,
还有说是曹操。
There is also saying it is Cao Cao.
曹也有时候曹操的曹就是曹操的曹去了。
Cao Sometimes Cao Cao's Cao is Cao Cao's Cao.
那个提手可能是这几个字，
That handle may be these words.
这个牌子其实特别有意思，
This brand is actually very interesting.
你看它上面写的字是五个字，
You see, the words written on it are five characters.
木默行清一，
Kiku-shiki Seiichi,
什么是木默行清？
What is Mu Mo Xingqing?
有清在汉代是厕所的意思，
It means that the Qing Dynasty was a toilet in the Han Dynasty.
这个名字很高雅啊，
This name is very elegant.
木默行清感觉是个很高级的东西。
Mu Moxingqing felt that he was a very high-end thing.
但行清是厕所，
But Xingqing is the toilet.
木默可能有推测说是乡椿木制成的厕所。
Mu Mo may have speculated that it was a toilet made of Xiangchun Wood.
但也有别的说法啊，
But there are other statements,
你看这边还有这个胡操的金，
Look, there is also this Hu Cao's gold here.
这个过去在网上有很多多人讨讨论过胡虎，
In the past, many people have discussed Hu Hu on the Internet.
就就以前用来这个涂脂抹粉的那个人啊，
Just the one who used to apply makeup before,
曹操还是挺爱美的。
Cao Cao still loves beauty quite a lot.
包括他那么曹家，
Including him, Cao's family,
后来他的那个女婿叫啥啊，
What's his son-in-law's name later?
何狼何燕和平书复粉，
He Lang and He Yan's book of peace is back,
何狼呀，
What wolf,
不也是土粉吗？
Isn’t it also rustic?
这件文物有意思，
This artifact is interesting.
你看像透明的玻璃片一样，
You look like transparent glass,
我们用夸克的 AI 相机来扫一下，
We use a quark, AI camera to scan it.
看看是什么。
See what it is.
你看 AI 相机直接给生成了。
You see, the AI ​​camera is generated directly.
这是曹操高陵遗址博物馆展出的云母片，
This is a mica piece exhibited at the Cao Cao Gaoling Ruins Museum.
然后把出土背景是曹操高陵形制推测可能是穿孔设计，
Then, the unearthed background is the shape of Cao Cao's Gaoling Mausoleum, which may be a perforated design.
用于当时的缝缀或固定御医，
Used for sewing or fixing the imperial physician at that time,
是帝王贵族的藏具，
It is the hidden tools of emperors and nobles.
而云母婴质地轻薄，
And the texture of Mica baby is light and thin.
防腐性能强，
Strong anti-corrosion performance,
常被用作御医的替代品，
Often used as a substitute for imperial physicians.
以降低制作成本或适应特殊需求。
To reduce production costs or adapt to special needs.
所以说我们看到的这个云母片，
So the mica slice we saw,
其实它是代替我们熟悉的金缕御医上的玉片的，
In fact, it replaces the jade tablets on the Imperial Doctor who are familiar with.
跟那个是一个作用。
It has the same function as that.
大家好，
Hello everyone,
这里是二零二五年五月下旬，
This is late May 2025.
我们来看一下曹操高陵门口，
Let’s take a look at the gate of Cao Cao’s Gaoling.
现在都有哪些贡品？
What tributes are there now?
首先还是依旧老演员布洛芬缓释片和布洛芬缓释胶囊这边还有人贴心的给了一个布洛芬颗粒的说明书。
First of all, the old actors still have ibuprofen sustained-release tablets and ibuprofen sustained-release capsules. Someone thoughtfully gave an instruction manual for ibuprofen granules.
好久没见，
Haven't seen each other for a long time,
不是广告啊。
Not an advertisement.
青梅煮酒论英雄也不知道是谁花里胡哨的，
I don’t know who is fancy and whistle when talking about heroes when I make green plum wine.
给了一个这样的布洛芬缓释胶囊，
I was given a sustained-release capsule of ibuprofen,
我也是第一次见啊，
It's the first time I've seen you.
快过期了，
It's almost expired,
还这边还有婴幼儿用的，
There are also infants and toddlers here.
上面还有一个布洛芬片儿夹在这个缝里。
There is also an ibuprofen piece on it that is sandwiched in this slit.
我来之前特地给你挂了一个专家号，
Before I came, I specially banned an expert number for you.
我问了一下，
I asked,
你这个病到底是咋回事。
What's going on with your disease?
而且人家专家说了，
And the experts said,
你不能吃布洛芬，
You can't take ibuprofen,
布洛芬只能用于暂时缓解你的病症，
Ibuprofen can only be used to temporarily relieve your condition.
是因为牙周炎引起的三叉神经和周围神经炎，
It is caused by periodontitis and trigeminal nerves.
你得吃这个唉等一下啊，
You have to eat this, wait a moment
你得吃这个甲钴胺胶囊，
You have to take this methylcobalamin capsule.
这个可以缓解和营养你的神经啊，
This can relieve and nourish your nerves.
你常吃这个才能有利于你的病症。
If you take this regularly, it will be beneficial to your illness.
你们老曹家就爱吃甜食，
Your Cao family loves sweets.
你的病也跟牙有关。
Your disease is also related to teeth.
所以我今天给你带来了牙齿洗护套装啊。
So I brought you a dental wash suit today.
首先第一个啊漱口水牙线儿童音乐牙膏、
First of all, mouthwash floss children's music toothpaste,
双效防蛀的牙膏，
Double-effect anti-causing toothpaste,
看到这个图案有没有什么一种亲切感？
Is there any sense of intimacy when I see this pattern?
哼东风不与周郎便铜雀春深锁二乔。
Humph, the east wind does not go with Zhou Lang, and the bronze bird spring locks the two Qiaos.
嗯，
Um,
好嗯，
Good laugh,
呃，
Well,
这次行程我们见过了这位纵横汉墨乱世的枭雄，
We have met this hero who is chaotic in the turbulent times of Han Dynasty and Ink.
那个曾经悲愤的写出白骨戮于野，
The once grief-angry writing about the bones killing in the wild,
千里无鸡鸣的义气儿郎最终间接撕裂了汉家四百年的华丽袍符，
The loyal man who had no rooster crowed thousands of miles eventually indirectly tore the gorgeous robe that had been in the Han family for four hundred years.
又在墓室里留下朴素至极的陈设与陪葬，
He also left behind simple furnishings and burials in the tomb.
烈士，
martyr,
暮年依旧壮心不已。
I still have ambitions in my old age.
但古往今来又有谁真的可得永年了呢？
But who has really achieved eternal life through ancient times?
投骨孤辘尽砖石英雄终究成过客。
The hero of bricks and quartz will eventually become a passerby.
本期视频到此结束，
This video ends here.
欢迎大家日常多多体验夸克 AI 逛博物馆也一定要记得提前下载。
Everyone is welcome to experience quarks more in daily life. You must remember to download them in advance when visiting museums when AI is visiting museums.
好夸克诸君留步，
Good quarks, please stay.
我们墓世见。
We see you in the world.